Khalid A. Khader

Full Stack Developer - Junior Machine Learning Engineer

Email: khalidalkhader@gmail.com Address: Palestine - Ramallah **Phone:** +970568807701 Date of birth: May 10, 2000 Nationality: Palestinian Link: https://www.linkedin.com/in/khalid-khader-3a8b43121/



OBJECTIVE

I'm Khalid, I'm a computer Engineer, and work as a junior Data Science and ML TA/Engineer at AXSOS AG, and I worked as a Full-stack Developer/TA, in AXSOS AG, I also trained as a front-end React JS developer at EXALT Technologies, and worked in a project in oracle PL/SQL for one year mainly in AI with Database for a web App. and also Im deliver many sessions with many popular academies in Palestine such as AXSOS Academy, TAP, Knowledge Academy.

EXPERIENCE

Palestine Ramallah Jul 2023 - Present

Full Time - DATA SCIENCE AND MACHINE LEARNNG ENGINEER/TA

AXSOS AG - Germany Stuttgart

Start working on data science and machine learning with basic knowledge of NumPy, Pandas, MatPlotlib, Seaborn, Folium, scikit learn, XGBOOST, LightGBM, Keras, Tensorflow, SHAP, LIMA, Stats Model, Tableau and PyTorch. I Worked on Brain Tumors Detection using open CV and Tensorflow with Keras project and working in Advanced Machine learning using some Deep learning ANN like CNN and RNN.

Ramallah - Gaza - Netherland Oct 2023 - Present

Professional Mentor TAP

Start as a Part Time professional mentor in Software development

Palestine Ramallah Nov 2000 - Present

Full Time - Full Stack Teaching Assistant / Developer

AXSOS AG - Germany Stuttgart

Full Stack Teaching Assistant. Assisting students with problem solving, different stacks, code review. Certified in Coding Dojo in MERN, Python (Django and Flask) stacks, and Java Spring boot stack. I worked a bit on development of the ALGOS LABS project for AXSOS Academy with a team of specialists in React TS, JAVA SPRING, Mongo, and Postgres database, and working on AI Sessions with some basic AI Apps.

Ramallah Oct 2023 - Present **Professional Mentor** TAP

Start as a professional mentor in Software development program

Palestine Jenin Sep 2021 - Jul 2022 SMART ADVISING SYSTEM - Part Time -Oracle Apex developer ARAB AMERICAN UNIVERSITY

Our System Created in APEX ORACLE, Using Artificial Intelligence Techniques. Our System aims to guide our CSE students of all student's educational levels. It will show the courses on the student's plan and the description of all courses. Check it here

EDUCATION

West Bank Jenin Sep 2018 - Sep 2022 BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SYSTEMS

ENGINEERING ARAB AMERICAN UNIVERSITY

(4 YEARS INSTEAD OF 5 WITH VERY GOOD) specialized in Web

Development and Database

BIRZEIT UNIVERSITY specialized in Machine Learning, Deep Learning and Data Science

Administration AAUP, Rami.hodrob@aaup.edu.

Dr. Mahmoud Obaid, Head of Computer System

Engineering AAUP, Mahmoud.Obaid@aaup.edu

MASTER OF COMPUTER ENGINEERING

West Bank Ramallah Nov 2022 - Present

LANGUAGES REFERENCES **English** Dr. Rami Hodrob, dean of Registration and

Advanced

Arabic Native

• Python Java

JavaScript

SKILLS

• SQL

• Git • Linux

Problem Solving

React

Java Spring

Machine Learning (Scikit-learn) • Data Science(Pandas, Matplotlib,

Numpy) • Deep Learning (TensorFlow)

Django

Flask

 React PL/SQL

PROJECTS

Academy with a team of specialists in React TS, JAVA SPRING, Mongo, and Postgres database. I worked on devloping a system created using APEX ORACLE, Using

I worked on development of the ALGO LABS project for AXSOS

Artificial Intelligence Techniques. The System aims to guide our CSE students of all student's educational levels. It will show the courses on the student's plan and the description of all courses. I worked on developing Deep Learning system that Detect Brain Tumors

using open CV and Tensorflow with Keras By Creating CNN model.

ACHIEVEMENTS

boost overall sales by 15% as 'Team Leader'.

- Consistently surpassed sales targets for 6 consecutive months. - Helped

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

I got Coding Dojo Certificate in MERN Stack (Mongo Database, Express JS, React JS, Node JS) with a red belt.

HONORS & AWARDS

In My Bachelor Level I got GPA more than 90% (3.67) 4 times in Bachelor of Computer Systems Engineering

PUBLICATIONS

Im working to publish research about brain tumors detection using CNN

PALESTINIAN DRIVER LICENSE

Active Since 2018